MOU, XIANGYANG

100 McChesney Ave, APT-F10 Troy, NY, 12180

≅:+1-314-541-5246 **⊠**:moux4@rpi.com

PROFILE SUMMARY

Ph.D student in the area of natural language processing, multimodality and human-computer interaction, with strong programming skills of Python, Matlab, Android, JavaScript, HTML and C/C++; doing research and applications on QA systems and cognitive systems by leveraging deep learning techniques

EDUCATION

Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute (RPI) Troy, NY
Ph.D candidate in Computer System Engineering

Aug 2017 - Current

 Washington University in St. Louis (WUSTL) St. Louis, MO Master of Science in Electrical Engineering

Jan 2015 - May 2016

Xidian University (XDU) Xi'an, China
Bachelor of Engineering in Electronic Information Engineering

Sept 2010 – Jul 2014

RECENT PROJECTS

Flexible Platform For Multiple Roles in Developing Dialogues for Language Learning

Mar 2019 – Current

- Designed a dialogue engine, optimized it for the second language learning, and published it as an online service with Flask, Socket.io and RabbitMQ
- Implemented RESTful APIs of the dialogue service for daily developments, testing and downstream applications
- Developed user-friendly tools and graph-based data visualization with Bootstrap and Vis. is for easy editing

Machine Teaching for Goal-oriented Dialogue System

Oct 2018 – May 2019

- Adopting a Markov model for dialogue manager and task manager
- Using supervised learning and weak supervised learning techniques to train the model with less data
- Leading 20 undergraduates to improve the dialogue system to be more domain-adaptive

A Framework of Collecting and Fusing Multi-Modal Data for Cognitive Analysis

May 2018 – August 2019

- Built a frame that can automatically detect and fuse multimodal data including multiuser location, speech, gesture, head pose and screen data
- Modularized the system and optimized the logic flow so that it is easy to scale up, add additional modalities and support multiple users scenarios in real time
- Provided utilities and API to serve as an infrastructure and offered support to multiple real-time applications

Mobile Eye Gaze Tracking

Sept 2017 – May 2018

- Developed an Android app for raw data collection, image preprocessing and online demo
- Used TensorFlow to train a model for eye gazing tracking, with model designed speficifically for mobile device
- Implement the simplified iTracker deep learning model on Android device
- Achieved an accuracy of more 60% on a 5-inch screen for 3x3 grid test.

Remote Accessible Home Surveillance System - MalloryEye

Jan 2017 - Mar 2017

- Built and maintained an AWS server and developed a project website for online access and management
- Developed Python programs on server to control a local camera for taking and uploading pictures
- Used CNN to do cat detection and prevent cats from entering kitchen and jumping onto dinning table

Android App Development

• Online Ultimate Tic Tac Toe on Google Play

Mar 2017

MOU, XIANGYANG

2:+1-314-541-5246

• Kismat Konnect – Dating App for South Asian Area

Aug 2016 – Oct 2016

Cocktail Party Hearing Aid by Microphone Array

May 2015 - Aug 2015

- Established a parallel-computing structure among computers and designed a parallel-computing algorithm, improving the computational ability 160 times
- Adopted cross-correlation algorithm, bringing a thousandfold increase in wave shifting speed with higher accuracy
- Optimized data process flow and achieved required real-time signal process

Peer-to-Peer Loan Analyzer

Aug 2014 - Dec 2014

- Collected and cleansed semi-structured raw data from hundreds of online personal loan platforms
- Provided modeling for platform reliability and safety analysis

Exercise Detection System Based on the MEMS Accelerometer

Jan 2014 - Jun 2014

- Designed a wearable hardware device with possessor, sensors, Bluetooth module and power
- Recognize dynamic patterns of different exercise including walking, running, falling and leaning
- Developed a matching Android App to collect data from wearable device, creating user-friendly interface in step counting, fall alerts, and related functions

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

| • | Embedded Control (ENGR 2350) | Jan. 2018 – May 2018 |
|---|--|------------------------|
| • | Image Processing (ECSE 4540) | Jan. 2018 – May 2018 |
| • | Embedded Control (ENGR 2350) | Sept. 2017 – Dec. 2017 |
| • | Computer Graphics (ECSE 4750) | Sept. 2017 – Dec. 2017 |
| • | Analysis and Programming Implementation Tutor | Jul. 2016 – Aug. 2016 |
| • | Introduction to Electronic Circuits Teaching Assistant | Jan. 2016 – May 2016 |
| • | Digital Signals Processing Teaching Assistant | Jan. 2016 – May 2016 |
| | | |

PUBLICATION & POSTER

- [7] Xiangyang Mou, Mo Yu, Shiyu Chang, Yufei Feng, Li Zhang, and Hui Su.
- "Complementary Evidence Identification in Open-Domain Question Answering". In ACL, 2020 (Under Review)
- [6] Xiangyang Mou, Brandyn Sigouin, Ian Steenstra, and Hui Su.
- "Multimodal Dialogue State Tracking By QA Approachwith Data Augmentation". In AAAI DSTC8 Workshop, 2019
- [5] Xiangyang Mou, Sylvia Hua, Nikhilas Murthy, and Hui Su.
- "A Flexible Platform for Multiple Roles in Developing Dialogues for Language Learning". In *IBM AI Horizons Colloquium*, 2019
- [4] Rahul R. Divekar, Xiangyang Mou, Lisha Chen, Maira G. Melina A. Guerra, and Hui Su.
- "Embodied Conversational AI Agents in a Multi-modal Multi-agent Competitive Dialogue". In IJCAI, 2019
- [3] Rahul R. Divekar, Jeffrey O. Kephart, Xiangyang Mou, Lisha Chen, and Hui Su.
- "You talkin'to me? A practical attention-aware embodied agent". In INTERACT, 2019
- [2] David Allen, Rahul R. Divekar, Jaimie Drozdal, Lilit Balagyozyan, Shuyue Zheng, Ziyi Song, Huang Zou, Jeramey Tyler, **Xiangyang Mou**, Rui Zhao, Helen Zhou, Jianling Yue, Jeffrey O. Kephart, and Hui Su
- "The Rensselaer Mandarin Project—a Cognitive and Immersive Language Learning Environment". In AAAI, 2019
- [1] Xiangyang Mou, Lisha Chen, Rui Zhao, Gyanendra Sharma, Dong Hu, Junjie Ding, Hui Su, Jeff Kephart.
- "A Systematic Way of Collecting and Fusing Multi-Modal Data for Cognitive Analysis Tasks". In *IBM AI Horizons Colloquium*, 2018

INDUSTRY EXPERIENCE

• Externship in IBM Sept. 2019 – Nov 2019